Guide to the Leo F. Flynn Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Leo F. Flynn papers
1890-1970
1949-1966
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
1540
1540-001
Flynn, Leo F.,$d1885-
1.09 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Leo F. Flynn was President of the Washington State Council of United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America and an organizer for the American Federation of Labor from 1938-1956. The collection spans the years 1890-1970 and contains records related to Flynn’s work with the American Federation of Labor, the Washington State Council of Carpenters, and the Washington State Personnel Board as well as materials related to his personal life.
Leo Francis Flynn (1885-1970) was born in Waseca County, Minnesota. He was President of the Washington State Council of United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America and an organizer for the American Federation of Labor from 1938-1956. He was married to Myra L. Flynn.
The collection is arranged into the following series:
SERIES I: AMERICAN FEDERATION OF LABOR
SERIES II: WASHINGTON STATE COUNCIL OF CARPENTERS
SERIES III: WASHINGTON STATE PERSONNEL BOARD
SERIES IV: PERSONAL PAPERS
The collection spans the years 1890-1970 (bulk 1949-1966) and contains records related to Flynn’s work with the American Federation of Labor, the Washington State Council of Carpenters, and the Washington State Personnel Board as well as materials related to Flynn’s personal life.
The following is a detailed description of materials within each series:
SERIES I: AMERICAN FEDERATION OF LABOR contains correspondence between Flynn and others regarding retirement benefits, personnel issues in the carpenters union, Flynn’s official letter to AFL-CIO President George Meany requesting retirement and related letters to AFL-CIO Secretary Treasurer William F. Schnitzler, and letters between Flynn and Oregon Governor Paul Patterson regarding a lumber dispute in 1955. Also included are news clippings and Flynn’s organizational membership ephemera.
SERIES II: WASHINGTON STATE COUNCIL OF CARPENTERS contains correspondence; official reports and financial statements of the council; election, organizational membership, and labor convention ephemera and printed material; a news clipping on the carpenters union and racketeering; and an artifact from the United Brotherhood of Carpenters & Joiners of America.
SERIES III: WASHINGTON STATE PERSONNEL BOARD contains correspondence between Flynn and Washington State Governor Arthur B. Langlie and the board’s official compensation plan.
SERIES IV: PERSONAL PAPERS contains correspondence between Leo and Myra Flynn and friends; assorted photographs of Flynn throughout his personal and professional life, including images of Flynn at labor conventions and at work with office staff, as well as individuals believed to be his wife Myra, other family members and friends, pets, and home exteriors; and a scrapbook likely compiled by Flynn containing assorted labor and non-labor related news clippings, including articles about Flynn’s work with the Washington State Council of Carpenters, as well as printed poems, cards, and event invitations.
Access to a portion of the records is restricted: For terms of access, contact Special Collections for details.
Donated by E. J. Comrada, 2/16/1971.
Flynn, Leo F.,$d1885-$vArchives; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America.$bWashington State Council; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington); American Federation of Labor$vArchives; Washington (State).$bPersonnel Board
Personal Papers/Corporate Records; Labor History; Labor Unions; Logging; Washington (State); Scrapbooks; Photographs
- AMERICAN FEDERATION OF LABOR, 1938-1966; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/4, 1/16)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1953-1966 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Seattle Post Intelligencer Press Release on Auditing of Union Funds, 1957 February 24 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - News Clippings: AFL and Leo Flynn, 1949,1955 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Ephemera: Certificate and Membership Card, 1938, 1953 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Correspondence - RESTRICTED, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 1/16)
- WASHINGTON STATE COUNCIL OF CARPENTERS, 1913-1970; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/5-1/8, 2/2)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Reports and Financial Statements, 1963-1965, 1970 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Ephemera and Printed Material, 1913, 1945, 1958-1969 (Box-folder 1/7)
  - News Clipping: Max Raddock and Senate Rackets Committee Hearing, 1958 February 20 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Artifact: Metal United Brotherhood of Carpenters & Joiners of America Logo, Undated (Box-folder 2/2)
- WASHINGTON STATE PERSONNEL BOARD, 1955-1959; SERIES III (Box-folder 1/9-1/10)
  - Correspondence Between Flynn and Governor Langlie, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Compensation Plan, 1959 July (Box-folder 1/10)
- PERSONAL PAPERS, 1890-1960; SERIES IV (Box-folder 1/11-1/15, 2/1)
  - Assorted Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Christmas Letter Poems and Address Lists, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Photographs (1 of 3), c. 1890-1960 (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Photographs (2 of 3), c. 1890-1960 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Photographs (3 of 3), c. 1890-1960 (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Scrapbook, c. 1928-1950 (Box-folder 2/1)